{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "Early versions of this device used rotating Nipkow disks. John Logie Baird pioneered the mechanical type of this device, which was improved upon by devices using image dissector tubes. Philo Farnsworth invented the electric version of this device, which contained cathode ray tubes that use superimposed red, green and blue to display color. For ten points, name this device whose early versions featured black and white broadcasts by NBC and CBS.",
      "answer": [
        "television",
        "TV"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This man rose to power with the support of the general Mucianus, who later encouraged this man to implement a tax on urinals. This ruler sent Agricola to govern Britain and extend Roman rule into Caledonia. This ruler was campaigning in Jerusalem when he learned of Vitellius’ ambitions to become emperor, prompting this man to return to Rome and end the Year of the Four Emperors. For ten points, name this man who founded the Flavian dynasty after the death of Nero.",
      "answer": "Vespasian or Titus Flavius Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, but do not"
    },
    {
      "question": "In this state, John Cruger fought against Nathaniel Greene and Thaddeus Kosciuszko at the Siege of 96. Alexander Stewart led a 1781 British victory along the Santee River in this state. Banastre Tarleton was defeated by a double envelopment by Daniel Morgan at this state’s Battle of Cowpens. During the Revolutionary War, Charles Cornwallis inflicted a defeat on Horatio Gates at the Battle of Camden in this state. For ten points, name this state where, in 1780, American forces surrendered in the Siege of Charleston.",
      "answer": "South Carolina"
    },
    {
      "question": "These sites were sustained by crops harvested by “neophytes.” The establishment of these sites forced nearby inhabitants into lands called reductions, where they would continue to live when these sites were divided into the rancho system. Defended by royal forts called presidios, 21 of these sites were linked by El Camino Real [ree-all]. Junipero Serra supervised conversion efforts at, for ten points, what Spanish religious outposts in California?",
      "answer": "Spanish missions in California"
    },
    {
      "question": "George H.W. Bush gave this Cabinet position to Elizabeth Dole, which she left in 1990 to become president of the American Red Cross. Current Secretary of Transportation Elaine Chao held this position for all eight years of George W. Bush’s presidency. The first female cabinet member held this post for the entirety of FDR’s time in office. For ten points, name this cabinet position held by Frances Perkins, who oversaw the passage of laws governing overtime wages.",
      "answer": "Secretary of Labor"
    },
    {
      "question": "This country commemorates a deadly 1952 student protest on Language Movement Day. A university in this country was attacked by tanks to flush out Chhatra League leaders in 1971. Yahya Khan launched Operation Searchlight to suppress the independence-seeking Awami League in this country, which was known at the time as East Pakistan. For ten points, name this country that, after gaining its independence from Pakistan in 1971, established its capital at Dhaka.",
      "answer": "Bangladesh"
    },
    {
      "question": "This composer wrote the score to a film about a nonexistent soldier during the reign of Paul I, as well as the music for an Eisenstein historical epic, Ivan the Terrible, whose Part II was suppressed by Stalin. This composer of Lieutenant Kij´e [kee-zhay] wrote a piece for narrator and orchestra in which the title boy’s grandfather is played by a bassoon and in which a canine swallows a duck whole. For ten points, name this Soviet composer of Peter and the Wolf.",
      "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev"
    },
    {
      "question": "One philosopher from this school claimed that human mysticism was a particularly ineffable quality; that work used the example of George Fox and the Quakers to argue that the origins of a religion did not reflect its value. The author of Varieties of Religious Experience belonged to this school of thought, whose namesake maxim argued that the “practical effects” of your conception were critical to rational thought. Charles Sanders Peirce [”purse”] and William James helped found, for ten points, what American philosophical school?",
      "answer": [
        "pragmatism",
        "word forms"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "ThismancommandedtheAgamemnon and,later,theCaptain underJohnJervisintheMediterranean fleet. An injury this man suffered at the Battle of Calvi left him blind in one eye; years later, this man claimed he didn’t see a signal to retreat after raising his telescope to that eye. A 169 foot tall Corinthian column in central London commemorates this man’s most famous battle, in which he was killed aboard the Victory. For ten points, name this British admiral who won the Battle of Trafalgar.",
      "answer": "Horatio Lord Nelson"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man confused the Lachine [la-sheen] Rapids as the Northwest Passage to China. This man brought Chief Donnacona with him on a return voyage to describe the riches of the northern Kingdom of Saguenay. This explorer was the first to describe the land that Iroquois inhabitants lived in as “Canada.” For ten points, name this Frenchman who discovered the mouth of the St. Lawrence River and mapped settlements at Quebec City and Montreal.",
      "answer": "Jacques Cartier"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One attempt to bankrupt this organization involved transferring its funds into the Alliance of Trade Unions, or OPZZ. After putting forth the 21 demands of the Inter-Enterprise committee, this organization argued for reforms with Wojciech Jaruzelski [voy-check yah-roo-zel-ski]. Shortly after a popular manager, Anna Walentynowicz, was fired, this organization went on strike at the Lenin Shipyard in Gdansk. Lech Walesa [lek vah-wen-sah] led, for ten points, what influential Polish labor union and political movement?",
        "answer": "Solidarity or Solidarnosc"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This aforementioned set of negotiations between Solidarity and the Polish government led to a namesake agreement legalizing trade unions and creating a Senate, which Solidarity promptly dominated after elections in June 1989.",
        "answer": "Round Table Talks or Round Table Negotiation, Agreement, etc."
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "John DeWitt’s support of this policy including the issuing of “Military Proclamation Number One.” This policy was implemented at sites like Heart Mountain and Topaz, as well as a site photographed by Ansel Adams and Dorothea Lange, Manzanar. Gordon Hirabayashi and Minoru Yasui both brought lawsuits against this policy. Executive Order 9066 put into effect, for ten points, what American policy of forced relocation and imprisonment of people of a certain Asian nationality during World War II?",
        "answer": "Japanese-American internment"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Supreme Court ruled that Japanese internment was constitutional in this 1944 case. This case has controversially not been officially overturned.",
        "answer": "Korematsu v. United States"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This empire’s last ruler, Brihadratha, was assassinated by Pushyamitra, who then founded the Shunga Dynasty. The second ruler of this empire ordered his son to capture the city of Takshashila. Megasthenes negotiated a peace agreement and marriage alliance in which this empire sent 500 elephants to the neighboring Seleucid Empire. A series of edicts in this empire were inscribed on pillars topped by lions and issued by its third ruler. For ten points, name this ancient Indian empire founded by Chandragupta and ruled by Ashoka [ah-shoke].",
        "answer": "Mauryan Empire"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Ashoka spread Buddhism in the Mauryan Empire, having converting to the faith after his bloody conquest of this kingdom in 260 BC.",
        "answer": "Kalinga"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man’s followers swore the Pledge of the Tree while one of his ambassadors was being held hostage. This commander’s troops fended off a far larger besieging army in the Battle of the Trench. This man defeated a contingent representing the Quraysh merchants at the Battle of Badr, after which he consolidated his base of power in Medina. Mecca was conquered by, for ten points, what leader who performed the Hijra migration and founded Islam?",
        "answer": "Muhammad"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This man, who served as a guard during the Battle of the Trench and the Battle of Badr, is nicknamed “The Truthful” and became the first Caliph after Muhammad’s death.",
        "answer": "Abu Bakr as-Siddiq"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This country’s city of List is one of four “compass communities” that host Unity Day celebrations to symbolize this country’s modern borders. Brocken Peak in this country’s Harz Mountains is said to be the site of witches’ meetings on Walpurgisnacht. An annual festival in the Theresienwiese celebrates this country’s consumption of bratwurst and beer. For ten points, name this country where Oktoberfest celebrations are the world’s largest annual festival.",
        "answer": "Federal Republic of Germany"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "All beer served at Oktoberfest must adhere to the standards set in this 1516 Bavarian law, which dictates that the only ingredients used in beer brewing are water, barley, and hops.",
        "answer": [
          "Reinheitsgebot",
          "German Beer Purity Law"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This speech calls for an “insurance-in” and a “bank-in” to strengthen black financial institutions, shortly after calling for boycotts of Wonder Bread and Coca-Cola. This speech opens with praise for “the best friend that I have in the world,” Ralph Abernathy, and ends with an ultimately foreboding note that “[he’s] seen the Promised Land,” though he “may not get there with you.” For ten points, name this April 3, 1968 speech, delivered in Memphis by Martin Luther King, Jr. the day before his assassination.",
        "answer": "I’ve Been to the Mountaintop"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The “I’ve Been to the Mountaintop” speech was given in response to a strike of these workers in Memphis.",
        "answer": [
          "sanitation workers",
          "equivalents related to garbage collection, waste collection, etc."
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Margaret Keogh [kee-oh] is believed to be the first civilian killed during this event, shot by forces commanded by William Lowe. Eoin [”Owen”] MacNeill attempted to cancel this event, greatly reducing the turnout of Volunteers. One side in this event had headquarters in the General Post Office. Patrick Pearse and James Connolly were among those executed in Killingham Gaol [”jail”] for leading this event, which began with the proclamation of an independent republic. For ten points, name this 1916 uprising centered in Dublin on a certain holiday, which sought Irish independence.",
        "answer": [
          "Easter Rising of 1916",
          "equivalents like uprising, rebellion, etc., for rising"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This man was caught attempting to smuggle German arms to the Easter Uprising and executed. He had earlier authored a report detailing Belgian abuses in the Congo.",
        "answer": [
          "Roger Casement",
          "Casement Report"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The writing of this work was prompted by Marjorie Spock’s legal actions on Long Island. Edwin Diamond, who was originally commissioned to co-write this book, scathingly critiqued its author after she was hired by the New Yorker to write an article on the same subject. This book highlighted bioaccumulation as a cause of the title, bleak condition of nature. For ten points, name this landmark 1962 environmental study that argued for the ban of DDT and other pesticides, written by Rachel Carson.",
        "answer": "Silent Spring"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This major producer of DDT lobbied heavily against Silent Spring when it was first published. This developer of nylon and Teflon merged with Dow in 2017.",
        "answer": [
          "DuPont",
          "DowDuPont"
        ]
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Early Pennsylvania",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "City that hosted the Constitutional Convention.",
          "answer": "Philadelphia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Religious group, including William Penn, that settled Pennsylvania.",
          "answer": [
            "Quakers",
            "Religious Society of Friends"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "King of England who granted William Penn the land in 1681, some two decades after he was restored to the throne.",
          "answer": "Charles II"
        },
        {
          "question": "Line that sets the Pennsylvania/Maryland border, named for its two surveyors.",
          "answer": "Mason-Dixon Line"
        },
        {
          "question": "Mosquito-borne disease that killed thousands of Pennsylvanians in fall 1793.",
          "answer": "yellow fever"
        },
        {
          "question": "1763 rebellion opposed by western Pennsylvania settlers via smallpox-infected blankets.",
          "answer": [
            "Pontiac’s Rebellion",
            "war, revolt, and other equivalents of rebellion"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Scots-Irish vigilante group that massacred the Susquehanna at the Conestoga Massacre.",
          "answer": "Paxton Boys"
        },
        {
          "question": "Native American tribe that granted the Walking Purchase to the Penn family, and which sold Manhattan to the Dutch.",
          "answer": [
            "Lenape",
            "Delaware"
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Treaty of Versailles",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "French city whose 1919 Peace Conference negotiated much of its terms.",
          "answer": "Paris"
        },
        {
          "question": "US President at the time of signing.",
          "answer": "Woodrow Wilson"
        },
        {
          "question": "British Prime Minister who helped negotiate it.",
          "answer": "David Lloyd George"
        },
        {
          "question": "Italian “Premier of Victory” who signed it.",
          "answer": "Vittorio Orlando"
        },
        {
          "question": "Controversial clause, listed as Article 231, that allowed countries to demand German reparations.",
          "answer": [
            "War Guilt Clause",
            "Article 231 if somehow given before mentioned"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "British economist who grimly predicted the Economic Consequences of the treaty.",
          "answer": "John Maynard Keynes , but be lenient"
        },
        {
          "question": "Province given to Japan that sparked the May Fourth Movement.",
          "answer": "Shandong"
        },
        {
          "question": "Group of Senators, including George Norris and Hiram Johnson, that strongly opposed ratification.",
          "answer": "Irreconcilables"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "The Mayans",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "European country whose conquistadors fought the Mayans on the Yucatan Peninsula.",
          "answer": [
            "Spain",
            "Spanish Empire"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Concept that the Mayans represented with dots and lines in a base 20 system.",
          "answer": [
            "numbers",
            "Mayan numerals",
            "anything related to mathematics"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Type of system represented by the Mayan Long Count, which assigned slightly over 394 years to a Baktun.",
          "answer": "Mayan calendar"
        },
        {
          "question": "Country home to the classical Mayan city of Tikal where modern Mayan peoples were involved in a decades-long civil war.",
          "answer": "Guatemala"
        },
        {
          "question": "Large Mayan city that is home to the step pyramid of El Castillo and the Temple of Kukulcan.",
          "answer": "Chichen Itza"
        },
        {
          "question": "Mayan text in the Quiche [kee-chay] language that tells of the mythological Hero Twins.",
          "answer": "Popul Vuh or Popul Wuj"
        },
        {
          "question": "Mayan ruler of Palenque [pah-len-kay] for 68 years, known as the Great.",
          "answer": [
            "Pacal the Great or K’inich Janaab Pakal I",
            "8 Ahau",
            "Sun Shield"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Mayan city, ruled by 18 Rabbit and Smoke Imix, that was the chief rival of Quirigua.",
          "answer": "Copan"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The leader removed from power in this event had campaigned with the slogan “Evolution in Continuity.” Shortly after this event began, a suspension bridge to Almada, colored similarly to the Golden Gate Bridge, was re-named for it. The (20 pts)",
        "beginning of this event was signaled with a Paulo de Carvalho song from the prior year’s Eurovision Song Contest. Marcello (10 pts)",
        "Caetano was removed from power in this event, which ended a regime began by Antonio Salazar. The Estado Novo ended with, for ten points, what peaceful 1974 Portuguese revolution?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Carnation Revolution",
        "25th of April Revolution"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In one of this man’s speeches, he lamented the suppression of the writings of Scott Nearing, Max Eastman, and John Work. In Canton, Ohio, this leader compared Wall Street to the German (20 pts)",
        "Junker class and urged people to resist the draft, after which he was prosecuted under the Sedition Act. The (10 pts)",
        "Pullman Strike was organized by, for ten points, what socialist who earned three percent of the popular vote in the 1920 Presidential election, despite being in prison?"
      ],
      "answer": "Eugene Victor Debs"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This country was the site of the 1983 Black July pogrom, which triggered a civil war. The first female ruler of an Asian nation, Queen Anula, ruled the Anuradhapura kingdom in what is now this country. The (20 pts)",
        "Pali Canon, an ancient Buddhist scripture, was recorded in this country after being composed in northern India. (10 pts)",
        "Kandy was the last independent kingdom in this modern country, which is connected to the mainland by Adam’s Bridge. For ten points, name this island country, known as Ceylon during its British occupation, found off the coast of India."
      ],
      "answer": "Sri Lanka"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A portrait of this man shows him wearing a billowing red cape in a storm as two cherubs stand behind him holding onto a red string. That Benjamin West portrait of this man was a study for a larger painting, never completed, that was to be donated to a (20 pts)",
        "hospital founded by him. This man created a drawing labeled with abbreviations of colonies next to the eight (10 pts)",
        "cut sections of a snake above the caption “Join or Die.” For ten points, name this founding father shown in the painting “Drawing Electricity out of the Sky” holding a key on a kite string."
      ],
      "answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) These events were governed by a two-thirds rule that led to a bitter conflict between the Wet and Dry factions in 1924. The McGovern-Fraser Commission was created to solve the problems that arose at one of these events that was marred by (20 pts)",
        "Robert Kennedy’s assassination three months earlier. At the 2016 version of this event, Khizr Khan, a Gold Star parent, criticized (10 pts)",
        "Donald Trump’s campaign promises. For ten points, name this quadrennial event at which politicians like Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton have been nominated to run for President by their party."
      ],
      "answer": "Democratic National Conventions or DNCs"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this event, Helene is killed by a rapist who bites her, though the rapist himself is killed by the apprentice of the wood carver Master Niklaus. This historical event provides the backdrop of Hermann Hesse’s novel (20 pts)",
        "Narcissus and Goldmund. Seven women and three men share a hundred stories with each other while fleeing this event in (10 pts)",
        "Florence in Giovanni Boccaccio’s Decameron. Early treatments of the Danse Macabre motif depict the ravages of, for ten points, what Medieval epidemic?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Black Death",
        "the black plague",
        "the bubonic plague"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this event, a Writers Union commission headed by Jaroslav Seifert investigated crimes against literary figures. This event prompted a promise of intervention in the Bratislava Declaration. The Two Thousand (20 pts)",
        "Words manifesto was issued during this period, whose end was protested by Jan Palach’s [yan pal-ok’s] self-immolation in Wenceslas Square. During this period, newly elected First Secretary Alexander (10 pts)",
        "Dubcek [doob-check] attempted to implement “Socialism with a human face.” For ten points, name this period of Czechoslovakian liberalization that was crushed by a 1968 Soviet invasion."
      ],
      "answer": "Prague Spring"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Vice Admiral William McRaven organized this event, which was planned for the night of the White House Correspondents Dinner. In the aftermath of this event, the perpetrators consulted the (20 pts)",
        "Saudi Arabian government while onboard the USS Carl Vinson before burying a corpse in the North Arabian (10 pts)",
        "Sea. A courier named Abu Ahmed al-Kuwaiti was tracked to discover the location of this event’s target, who was codenamed “Geronimo.” For ten points, name this May 2, 2011 event in which members of SEAL Team Six killed the leader of Al-Qaeda."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "assassination or killing, shooting, etc. of Osama bin Laden",
        "Operation Neptune Spear"
      ]
    }
  ]
}